Weilue Luo

□ (+44) 07543295595 | work.luoweilue@gmail.com | • Redcxx | • luoweilue.com | • weilueluo.com

Summary_

A versatilist that passionate about coding in general, specializing in full-stack development and interested in machine learning. Solid knowledge of Java, Python, Javascript, data structures, algorithms, and writing clean and maintainable code; also a fast learner that can adapt to new technology stacks and languages quickly.

Education

University College London

London, UK

COMPUTER SCIENCE - MSc COMPUTER VISION (DISTINCTION - EXPECTED AVG. 85+%)

Sep. 2021 - Present - Sep. 2022

• Relevant Modules: Machine Learning for Visual Computing, Image Processing, Networked Systems, Machine Vision, Computer Graphics, Perception and Interface, Robot Vision and Navigation, and Virtual Environment.

University of Manchester

Manchester, UK

COMPUTER SCIENCE - BSc ARTIFIAL INTELLIGENCE (DISTINCTION - AVG. 83%)

Sep. 2019 - Sep. 2021

• Relevant Modules: Mathematics, Operating System, Algorithms and Complexity, Databases, Logic and Modelling, Software Engineering, Imperative Programming, Object-oriented Programming, Machine Learning and Optimization, Al and Games, Computer Vision, Graphics and Image Processing, Distributed Computing, Mobile System, and Cryptography.

Bellerbys College

Brighton, UK

FOUNDATION - COMPUTING (1ST IN COHORT)

Jan. 2019 - Jun. 2019

• Relevant Modules: Decision & Pure Maths, Databases, Programming & Code, Web Design, and System Analysis.

Skills

Proficiency Java ≈ Python > Javascript > GLSL = HTML/CSS.

Java JUnit, Hamcrest, Lombok, Guava, Spring, Jackson.

Python Pytorch, Numpy, Matplotlib, Jupyter.

Javascript NodeJs, ReactJs, ThreeJs, NextJs, SASS/SCSS.

DevOps Git, CR, AWS, Scrum, Docker, Github Actions.

Spoken Chinese and Cantonese (native), English (decent), Japanese (beginner).

Other Proficient with markdown, Unix environment, latex, and various IDE like VSCode and Jetbrains'.

Experience

NoGhost London, UK

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER - PYTHON

Jun. 2022 - Present - Sep. 2022

- Assigned as the master project.
- Implement a number of state-of-the-art ML papers such as U-Net Pix2pix, AlacGAN and Sketch Simp to aid artists' development process.
- Built the preprocessing, training and inference pipeline from scratch to manipulate raw data.

Amazon - Alexa Cambridge, UK

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERNSHIP - JAVA AND PYTHON

Jun. 2021 - Sep. 2021

- Built and embedded an experiment framework into the existing Question-Answering pipeline.
- Conducted experiments with real customer traffic, written multiple scripts to preprocess, analyze and visualize over 10 GBs of customer responses, and presented a proof-of-concept report for novel answering techniques that received positive feedback.
- Developed an efficient workflow for future experiments, reduced experiment deployment time needed from days to hours; coordinated and discussed design decisions with internal teams.
- · Received return offer.

Amazon - Item Safety

Edinburgh, UK

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERNSHIP - JAVA AND PYTHON

Jun. 2020 - Sep. 2020

- · Designed and developed multiple procedures to aggregate concise datasets from 3 billion item records daily using Spark-based tools.
- Reduced time-consuming ad-hoc graph analysis from tens of minutes to seconds by developing an effective modern visualization dashboard using Elastic Search and Kibana.
- Enhanced progress tracking, performance evaluation, long-term maintenance and UI experience by designing and building an API package for automating the creation of visualization components and dashboards.
- · Received return offer.



Personal Websites London, UK

SOLE DEVELOPER - HTML/CSS, JAVASCRIPT, AND GLSL

Jun. 2020 - Present

- · Written websites from scratch using various technologies such as reactJs, nextJs, threeJs, sass, postcss, and pugJs.
- Visits https://luoweilue.com (simple) or https://weilueluo.com (fancy).

Machine Learning with Pytorch

London, UK

SOLE DEVELOPER - PYTHON

Nov. 2020 - Present

- Time Series Prediction Generate Monophonic and Polyphonic piano music via various models & techniques, including LSTM, skip connection & attention. Report can be found at https://soundcloud.com/kallzvx/sets.
- Image Classification Transfer learning based on a pre-trained resnet, over 90% accuracy with 10 classes of 1000 training samples.
- Image Denosing Built a Encoder-Decoder based network, result PSNR improved by 100%(15-30) compared to traditional Gaussian denosing technique.
- Other Familiar with linear/polynomial linear/logistic regression/classification; clustering algorithms like KMeans and Meanshift; SVM, kSVM, and wrote a simple network network from scratch.

First Person Virtual Reality Game - Bouncing Ray

London, UK

LEAD DEVELOPER - C#

Mar. 2022 - Apr. 2022

• Lead a team of 4 to build a first person Virtual Reality game based on the ubiq framework (https://github.com/UCL-VR/ubiq). Project can be found at https://github.com/HengyiWang/COMP0113-BouncingRay.

Local Nameserver London, UK

SOLE DEVELOPER - PYTHON

Feb. 2022 - Mar. 2022

Written a local nameserver that able to resolve any IPv4 address according to RFC 1034 and RFC 1035 specification. The project can be found
at https://github.com/Redcxx/local-nameserver.

Poisson Image Editing

London, UK

SOLE DEVELOPER - PYTHON

Dec. 2021 - Jan. 2022

• Implemented the Poisson Image Editing paper. Including techniques such as naive filling; import & mixing gradient; texture flattening, colour isolation & illumination. The project can be found at https://github.com/Redcxx/poisson-image-editing.

Propositional Logic Utils

Manchester, UK

SOLE DEVELOPER - JAVA

Oct. 2019 - Nov. 2019

• A tools for parsing and manipulating propositional logic formulas, supports conversion to normal forms, push negations, tautology and contradiction checks and truth table generation. The project can be found at https://github.com/Redcxx/PropositionalLogicUtils.

Image Downloader

Manchester, UK

SOLE DEVELOPER - PYTHON

Jun. 2019 - Aug. 2019

• Designed and implemented an API supports automatic login, multithreading downloading, various format parsing and filter images, along with a graphical user interface. The project can be found at https://github.com/Redcxx/Pikax.

Photographic Mosaic

Manchester, UK

SOLE DEVELOPER - PYTHON

Aug. 2019 - Aug. 2019

• Built a library for generating photographic mosaic, capable of processing and matching over 30k of images within 3 minutes, supports various RGB-based and LAB-based color difference algorithms. The project can be found at https://github.com/Redcxx/Mosaic-Pics.

MP3 Music Player Manchester, UK

SOLE DEVELOPER - JAVA

Mar. 2019 - Jun. 2019

• A simple MP3 player with GUI, supports functionalities, such as play, pause, restart, and upload custom songs. The project can be found at https://github.com/Redcxx/MP3_Music_Player

Collaborate Live Manchester, UK

LEAD DEVELOPER - HTML/CSS, JAVASCRIPT, AND PYTHON

Jan. 2019 - Mar. 2019

- Directed a team of 7 students to build a web application for a code-based interview. Designed and implemented all core functionalities including real-time chatting, coding, and drawing with collaborators, supports online code compilation and web-embed terminal.
- Awarded 1st place in most appealing idea and highest technical quality prize out of 37 teams.

Other

SOLE DEVELOPER

• More projects can be found at my github https://github.com/Redcxx.